In the fight for equal rights, an ordinary woman
achieves something extraordinary.
Made in Dagenham is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Nigel Cole.
A dramatization of the 1968 strike at the Ford Dagenham car plant, where female
workers walked out in protest against sexual discrimination.
Rita O'Grady, played by Sally Hawkins.
Albert Passingham, played by Bob Hoskins.
Barbara Castle, played by Miranda Richardson.
Connie, played by Geraldine James.
Lisa Hopkins, played by Rosamund Pike.
Brenda, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Made in Dagenham is a 2010 British comedy-drama film directed by Nigel Cole, written by William Ivory, and starring Sally Hawkins, Bob
Hoskins, Miranda Richardson, Geraldine James, Rosamund Pike, Andrea Riseborough, Jaime Winstone, Daniel Mays and Richard Schiff.
It dramatises the Ford sewing machinists strike of
1968 that aimed for equal pay for women.
Its theme song, with lyrics by Billy Bragg, is performed by Sandie
Shaw, a native of the area and former Ford Dagenham clerk.
A stage musical version of the film opened at London's Adelphi Theatre in 2014.
The film explores themes of strike, based on true
story, essex, labor strike, machinist.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.